SONGYU WANG

3 Blu Harbor Blvd • Redwood City, CA 94063 • (812) 201-9470 • wangsongyuf@gmail.com songyu-wang.github.io • linkedin.com/in/wangsongyu

SUMMARY

Software test engineer (quality assurance specialist) with two years of experience in test strategy design, test automation, test plan, test execution(manual and automated) and test framework/tool development in the highly regulated medical industry in a SCRUM/Agile environment. Deep understanding of functional testing with behavior driven development and test driven development. Strong technical acumen with extensive defect and bug identification, triage, reporting and verification exposure. Oversee verification and validation regularly for web applications, API services, etc.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Rose-Hulman Institute of Technology

Terre Haute. IN

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science and Software Engineering (2018)

GPA: 3.73

Scrum.org | Professional Scrum Product Owner I (2019) & Professional Scrum Master I (2018)

Triplebyte | Generalist Software Engineering (2019)

Microsoft | MTA: Software Development Fundamentals (2016)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Selenium HTML/CSS/Javascript Cypress Behave

AWS Mac/Linux/Windows OS lava Pvthon MySQL

GIT Ienkins Docker

EXPERIENCE

May 2017 - Present

HeartFlow. Inc

Redwood City, CA

Software Engineer in Test

Iul 2018 - Present

- Oversee quality and testing for platforms and services' components in a SCRUM/Agile environment for a medical technology company that develops software used to create 3D models of coronary arteries to analyze blockages and the impact on blood flow
- Support development and verification of three web applications, three backend/API services and four workflow/product-related components
- Maintain and refactor existing legacy test frameworks to improve stability and speed, continuously deliver new features for newer frameworks
- Design manual and automated tests using Python and JavaScript to refine and verify product requirements prior to launch/implementation
- Discover and manage internal and external defects and bugs
- Conduct verification/validation activities, including developing and executing test plans, reviewing results and writing reports, and collaborate with cross-functional teams to perform functional, regression, and system-level testing, and ensuring all test-related documentation meets the current corporate and federal regulations
- Prepare Test /Risk Traceability Reports to document test execution outcomes and trace each product requirement and risk contributor/mitigator to the test

Software Engineer in Test - Intern

May 2017 - Aug 2017

 Designed and executed manual and automated tests to verify web application (frontend) product requirements

Prior intern and part-time work experience are omitted to conserve space. See https://songyu-wang.github.io/ for details

- Software Intern Rose-Hulman Ventures (Feb 2017 May 2017)
- Teaching Assistant Rose-Hulman Institute of Technology (Mar 2017 May 2018)
- Software Intern Pansoft Co. Ltd. (Jun 2016 Jul 2016)